Previously on "Better Call Saul..."
는 생략...
We'd be working on your case.
Chuck wouldn't like it.
Chuck has no say in this.
This deal he's doing with you,
he's doing outside his crew.
He doesn't want his bosses to know.
I had a baseball card collection...
All gone!
You're sure they weren't
looking for anything else?
Wouldn't it be great if we
could do that every night?
Yes, but we can't.
We could have gone home
with $800,000, tax free!
Your point being?
Why didn't we?
James McGill.
Clifford Mane.
Just Jimmy.
- Howard.
- 좋은 아침!
- Morning!
McGill 씨에게 배달 왔습니다.
Delivery for McGill.
여기서 뭐해?
What're you doing here?
아, 이거 오랜만이군.
Ah, it's been a while.
그냥 안부인사 겸 들러봤어.
Thought I should come in and check on you.
내가 아까 음악을 들었던 것 같은데?
Did I hear music?
- 흠?
- 아냐, 아냐.
- Hmm?
- No, no.
난 그냥... 그거 들어줄게.
I was just... ?let me get that for you.
- 만나서 반가워, Howard.
- 오, 나도.
- Good to see you, Howard.
- Oh, likewise.
정말 보고싶었어, 내 친구.
You are sorely missed, my friend.
부담갖지 말라구.
Don't take that as any undo pressure.
음, 다음 주에 한 두 시간 정도
갈까 했는데.
Um, I'm thinking of maybe coming in
for an hour or two next week.
상황 봐서 말야.
Maybe kind of play it by ear.
음, 너만 괜찮다면.
Well, ?I-if you feel comfortable.
내 말은, 우린 너가 오는 게 당연히 좋지.
I mean, we certainly would love to have you.
우린 뭐든 좋아.
We will take anything we can get.
내가 언제 되는 지 알아보고
Ernesto가 너한테 미리 알려주도록 할게.
I'll figure out a day and get
Ernesto to give you a heads up.
그거 좋네.
That sounds great.
Ernie는 잘 있어?
How's Ernie working out?
어, 그는 잘 지내. 전반적으로.
Uh, he's been fine, for the most part.
멋지군.
Excellent.
샌드파이퍼 관련된 건 제대로 되고 있어?
Everything on track with, uh, Sandpiper?
잘 되고 있지.
Moving along.
Davis & Main이, 어... 굉장히 잘 해주고 있어.
Davis & Main are, uh...
Really pulling their weight.
그들이 잘 할거야.
Well, they better.
이건 복잡한 사건이니까.
It's a complex case.
음, 확실히 두 명이서 할 일은 아니었지, 그건 확실해.
Well, it's definitely not
a two-man job, that's for sure.
Jimmy에 대해 들은 건 없어?
Anyone, uh, heard from Jimmy?
소식을 듣긴 했지, 응. 그랑 얘기했었어.
I have, yes. I've talked to him.
잘 지내?
How is he?
Howard: 그는 잘 지내.
He's fine.
잘 하고 있어.
Doing well.
말이 나와서 그런데... 소식이 하나 있어.
Speaking of which... I have some news.
Jimmy는 Davis & Main에서 일해.
He's working at Davis & Main.
뭘 하는데?
Doing what?
오, 변호사로 일한다고.
Oh, working as an attorney.
흠.
Hm.
Clifford Main이 Jimmy를 고용했어?
Clifford Main hired Jimmy?
응.
Mm-hmm.
공정히 말해서, 그는 반신반의 했지만,
Clifford가 Jimmy에게 기회를 한 번 주기로 했어.
To be fair, he had his doubts,
but he's giving Jimmy a chance.
Clifford가 직원들한테 고객 응대를 시켰는데,
He had his own people doing client outreach,
샌드파이퍼 거주자들하고 얘기할 때마다
but every time they would talk
to a Sandpiper resident,
Jimmy의 이름이 나오더라구.
Jimmy's name would come up.
그게 그러니까, 그는...
You know, he...
- 그 노인네들, 그들은 그냥...
- 그들이 Jimmy를 좋아하는군.
- Those old folks, they just...
- They love him.
- 응, 그런거지.
- 으음.
Yeah, they do. ?mm-hmm.
게다가, 내 생각에 Clifford는
이게 좋은 건수라 생각하는 것 같아.
Plus, I guess cliff thought
it would be a good idea
for the case to have that sort of, uh...
그... 지속할 수 있는.
You know... continuity.
음.
Mm.
Jimmy는 확실히 사람들을 잘 다루지.
Jimmy certainly has a way with people.
확실히 그래.
He does.
Davis & Main에서 그의 배경에 대해 걱정하진 않던가?
They're aware of his background
at Davis & Main?
그의 학벌이나?
His education?
숨김 없이 말하자면,
In the spirit of full disclosure,
사전에 Clifford랑 얘기했었어.
Cliff did talk to me beforehand.
난 조금의 사정도 봐주지 않았다구.
I didn't pull any punches.
완벽하게 판을 만들려고 했어.
I tried to paint a complete picture.
그치만 내가 방해할 수가 없더라구.
But I didn't stand in the way.
당연히 못 했겠지.
Of course not.
너도 할 수 없었을거야.
Nor should you.
사실대로 말하자면...
Truth be told...
Kim Wexler가 밀어붙였어... 매우 강하게.
Kim Wexler pushed for this... hard.
하지만 난 그러지 않았어, 어,
그러니까, 방해했다고.
But I didn't, uh,
you know, stand in the way.
파트너 트랙이야?
Partner track?
내가, 어...
I would, uh...
응.
Yeah.
그런 것 같아.
Assume so.
멋지네.
That's great.
Jimmy에게 잘 됐어.
Good for Jimmy.
Charlie Hustle, 그치?
Charlie Hustle, right?
맞아.
Yep.
?Yep.
음, 이제 방해하지 말아야겠군.
Well, I'll get out of your hair.
Ernie가 준 목록에서 더 추가해달라고 할 건 없고?
Anything else you need me
to add to Ernie's list?
모두 괜찮아. 딱 좋아.
No. All set. All good.
들러줘서 고맙네, Howard.
Thanks for coming by, Howard.
언제든지. 난 너가 정말 그리워.
Any time. You truly are missed.
압박하는 건 아니야.
No pressure.
♪
번역포럼 콩냥
영어자막출처 oykubuyuk www.addic7ed.com
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
Francis: HHM과의 서류 검토가 조정될 것입니다.
Document review
will be coordinated through HHM.
지금까지, 다음과 같은 서류들이
To date, the following documents
샌드파이퍼로부터 요구되었으며
have been requested from Sandpiper
우리의 초기 탄원서의 일부로 쓰일 것입니다.
as part of our initial discovery petition.
첫 번째... 과거부터 현재까지의 거주자 임대 계약서를
모든 샌드파이퍼 지부로부터 받았습니다.
One... resident lease
agreements, past and present,
from all Sandpiper locations.
두 번째... 샌드파이퍼가 이용했던 모든 물건 공급처에서
청구서와 거래 문서를 받았습니다.
Two... invoices and transaction documents
from all supply companies used by Sandpiper.
세 번째... 샌드파이퍼에 있는 자판기들에 대해
과거부터 현재까지의 모든 목록을 받았습니다.
Three... list of all past and present
official Sandpiper vendors.
네 번째... 샌드파이퍼와 배급업체간의
모든 사업적 협의서와 계약서를 받았습니다.
Four... any and all business
agreements and contracts
between Sandpiper and its distributors.
다섯 번째... 거주자들의 사회보장연금 수령액에 대한 기록.
Five... records of residents'
social security check receipts.
여섯 번째... 용돈 지급 내역.
Six... allowance transaction statements.
일곱 번째... 관련 없는 물품이 거주자들에게 청구된...
Seven... resident invoices
non-related to sup...
Kim: 새로운 모습이 맘에 들어.
I'm loving the new look.
산타페는 어때?
How's Santa Fe?
이건, 어...
It's, uh...
이건... 이건 진짜...
It's... It's really...
봤지? 내가 뭐라 했어?
See? What'd I tell you?
멋진 곳이지?
Nice place?
임시 회사치곤 최고야.
The finest in temporary corporate housing.
기다릴 수가 없군.
Can't wait to see it.
나 HHM을 떠날지도 모르겠어.
Maybe I should leave HHM.
편한 D&M 기차에 올라타야지.
Get on that cushy D&M train.
이거 완전 편해.
It is very cushy.
놀라워.
It's amazing.
Jimmy...
정말 잘 됐어.
I'm so happy for you.
고마워.
Than.
있지, 상황이 정말 좋아졌어.
You know, things are really turning around.
난 심지어 내 집도 살까 싶어.
I'm even thinking of looking, you know,
my own place to buy.
- 산타페에?
- 아직 정하진 않았어.
- In Santa Fe?
- Not sure yet.
아마 음, Albuquerque에 좀 더 가까운 곳이나...
Maybe someplace, uh, closer to Albuquerque
두 곳 모두 자주 가니까.
since I'm going between the two so much.
좋네.
Okay.
그래서, 중간 지점이라는거지.
So, halfway points.
음... 나는 생각하고 있었어, 어...
Um... ?yeah, I was thinking, uh...
- 오, 잠깐, Corrales는 어때?
- Corrales.
- Oh, wait, what about Corrales?
그치, 멋지고 작은 한 층 짜리 집 하나 얻어서
Yeah, get a nice, little bungalow,
혹은 그렇게 작지 않아도 되고.
or maybe not so little.
크고, 탁 트여 있는 건?
Big, open floor plan.
나는 내 기를 방해하는 벽이 없으면 좋겠어.
I don't want any walls
disrupting my chi, yeah.
어, 하지만 나는 정말 확실하게
Uh, but I'm thinking I definitely want
적당한 크기의 괜찮은 공간이 있으면 좋겠어.
자연을 느낄 수 있게.
some decent acreage,
get in touch with nature.
말들.
Horses.
해봐. 말을 가질 수 있다구.
Come on. You could get horses.
그거 완전 멋질거야.
Man, that would be so amazing.
너무 비싸. 그것들은, 어, 귀리... 맞지?
Too expensive. They, uh,
all the oats... right?
말들이 항상 먹는 게 귀리지?
It's oats ?that they're always eating?
- 그럴만한 가치가 있어.
- 그리고 편자에다가.
It's worth it. ?and the horseshoes.
넌 편자를 가져다가 망치로
그걸 못 박아야 한다구.
You have to get them shoes
and nail them with a hammer.
- 그거 완전 할만해.
- 이건...
- It's totally worth it.
- It's...
시골에서 말도 타고
Long ride through the country
해질녘에 파티오(집 뒤의 테라스)에서
한 잔의 와인을 마시면서...
and then glass of wine
on the back patio at sunset.
오, 우리 화덕도 하나 필요할거야.
Oh, we should get one of those smokers.
몇 날 몇 일을 바베큐 해 먹을 수 있어.
We could just barbecue for days.
그래. 우리 확실히 화덕을 구해야겠어.
Yeah. We definitely Got to get a smoker.
좋아, 그럼...
All right, well...
난 응접실로 가볼게.
I got to go to the salon.
내 새 회사 차를 가져다준댔어.
They're delivering my new company car.
어우, 진심이야?
Ugh, are you serious?
- 뭐가?
What?
Jeeves, 내 순금 비행선 어딨나?
Jeeves, ?where's my solid-gold blimp?
아니, 그거 말고. 다른 거.
No, not that one. The other one.
질투하기는.
Jealous.
완전히.
Totally.
아, 잊을뻔했다. 선물 줄 거 있어. 잠깐만 기다려.
Oh, I forgot.
?I got you a present. One sec.
완전 이쁘게도 포장했네.
Such a beautiful wrapping job.
열기 부끄러운데.
It's a shame to open it.
이거 선물이야. 고마워하라구.
It's a gift. Be grateful.
세상에서 "두 번째로" 멋진 변호사
실제 이런 것처럼 행동해.
Just keeping it real.
봐봐.
Come on.
두 번째는 그래도 여전히 매우, 매우 좋아.
Second is still very, very good.
좋아.
All right.
고마워.
Thanks.
오늘 밤에 볼까?
See you tonight?
아마도.
Maybe.
너가 일만 잘 끝내면.
If you play your cards right.
안녕, 이쁜이.
Hello, beautiful.
어때요, 아가씨들?
What do you think, ladies?
네, 저도 알아요, 그쵸?
Yeah, I know, right?
이거 모두 가죽에다가,
It's got all leather interior,
추운 아침을 위한 열선 깔린 시트에요.
heated seats for those cold desert mornings.
이게 바로 천국이죠.
This must be what heaven looks like.
이봐요!
Hey!
작별의 포옹이라도?
Goodbye hug?
싫어?
No?
좋아, 그래, 눈물은 포기하고,
All right, well, forgo the tears
"다음에 봐요"라고 하자고.
and just say, "till we meet again."
분명 맞을텐데.
Must be metric.
이봐요!
Hey!
여기서... 여기서 뭐 합니까?
What... What are you doing here?
여기서 일합니다.
I work here.
오. 좁은 세상이군.
Oh. Small world.
그래서, 여기가 경찰서 주차장 맞나요?
So, is this the parking lot
for the police station?
네.
It is.
그들이 인증한 곳인지는 잘 모르죠?
You don't know if they validate, do you?
그냥 여기 근처에서 돌아다니면서
Why don't you pull around over there,
대화 좀 나누지 그래요.
and we'll have a little talk.
아, 좋아요.
Uh, okay.
여기에 왜 온거요?
Why are you here?
경찰관이랑 해결할 일이 있어요.
I... I have business with the police.
그 일이라는 게 무엇이오?
And what business might that be?
음, 당신이 꼭 알아야겠다면,
저 도둑 맞았어요.
Well, if you must know, I was robbed.
누군가가 집에 침입해서 제 걸 훔쳐갔죠.
Somebody broke into my house
and stole my property.
당신의 약이군.
Your drugs.
네, 근데 저 진짜 확실하게
경찰한테 절대 말하지 않았어요.
Yeah, but obviously
?I didn't tell the cops that.
전 바보가 아니거든요.
I'm not stupid.
이미 경찰하고 얘길 했소?
You've already spoken to them?
두 명이 집에 들렀어요.
A couple of them came by my house.
하지만 제가 신경 쓰는 건
약이 아니라구요.
But it's not the drugs that I care about.
제 말은, 제가 신경쓰는 건.
I mean, I care.
제 야구 카드에요.
It's my baseball cards
전 그걸 되찾고 싶어요.
I need back.
- 야구 카드?
- 네.
- Your baseball cards?
- Yes.
저한테 완전 비싼 야구 카드 콜렉션이 있는데,
I have a very valuable
collection of baseball cards,
누군가가 그걸 훔쳐갔어요.
and someone stole them.
당신한테 이런 말 하는 게
별로 놀랍지도 않겠지만
I guess I shouldn't be surprised
I have to tell you this.
이거 완전 안 좋은 생각이오.
But it's probably a bad idea
당신이 경찰한테 말하려 하는 게
that you willingly talk to the police,
범죄를 포함한 모든 걸 말하게 될 거란 말이지.
being a criminal and all.
전 범죄자라 여기 온 게 아니에요.
I'm not here as a criminal.
전 피해자로 여기 온 거라구요.
I'm here as a crime victim.
단지 제가 가끔 약을 조금 판다고 해서
Just because I occasionally sell
some pharmaceuticals,
범죄로부터 보호 받을 권리가
사라진 건 아니잖아요?
I no longer have a right
to protection from crime?
그리고 저는 경찰관들이랑 대화할 때
엄청 조심히 말했다구요.
And I was very careful
when I talked to them.
그들은 내가 하고 있는 다른 일에
대해 알지도 못할거에요.
I... they have no idea
about my other business.
당신에 대한 보고서 작성이 끝난거면,
대체 여기 왜 왔소?
If you already made your report,
why are you here?
그들이 절 호출했어요.
They called me.
몇 가지 질문이 있대요.
They have a few more questions.
경찰관들이 도둑을 잡기 위해 엄청 헌신적이네요.
They are very dedicated
to finding this thief.
당신이 이런 일에 처음이니 설명해 주겠소.
Since you're new to this,
let me explain it to you.
그들은 당신을 함정에 빠뜨리려는거요.
They've invited you on a fishing trip.
그게 뭔데요? 함정?
What's that? A fishing trip?
이 경찰들은 당신 카드를 찾는 데에는 관심 없소.
Those cops have no interest in
helping you get your cards back.
당신은 분명히 의심 받고 있는거요.
You're obviously under suspicion.
그들이 눈치 챌 수 있는 게 단 하나도 없었다구요.
There was nothing there for them to see.
우리가 나눴던 마지막 대화를 기억하시게나.
I refer you ?to our previous conversation
그리고 이 깜빡이는 네온 사인 차량은
"마약 딜러"라고 말하는 거나 마찬가지야.
and this blinking neon sign of a
vehicle that says "drug dealer."
그들은 당신을 의심하고 있소.
They suspect you.
그들이 당신을 안으로 데려간 다음,
친구인 척 할테지.
They will get you in there,
pretend to be your friend,
그리고 당신을 일부러 안심시킬거요.
lull you into a false sense of security,
그리고 그들은 당신을 점점 죄어올걸세.
and then they will sweat you.
그리고 당신은 붙잡힐거요.
And you will break.
전... 저는...
I don't... I...
전 동의하지 않아요.
I disagree.
논쟁할 가치도 없소. 당장 집으로 가시오.
Not open for debate. You go home now.
하지만 전 약속이 있는걸요.
But I have an appointment.
깨버리시오.
Break it.
그리고 그들이 당신에게 전화하면,
전화를 받지도 마시오.
And if they call you,
do not answer the phone.
그치만 제 야구 카드는요?
But what about my baseball cards?
- 일 하느라 드는 비용이라 생각하시오.
- 싫어요!
- Cost of doing business.
- No!
싫어요!!
No, no, no!
전 그걸 되찾을거에요!
I am getting those back!
이 정도 위험은 감수할거에요!
I will take the risk!
아뇨, 하지 마시오.
No, you won't.
그렇게 한다면 내 행복도
위험에 몰아넣는거란 말이오.
Because then you'll be putting
my well-being at risk.
전 해야만해요!
I have to!
전... 전...
I... I...
그 카드들요?
Those cards?
그것들 중 몇 개는 제 아빠 거라구요.
Some of them were my dad's.
전... 전 그것들을 되찾을거에요.
I... I am getting them back.
전 되찾을거라구요.
I'm getting them back.
내가 당신 카드들을 찾아주지.
I'll find your cards.
그건...
Is... ser...
당신이 하겠다구요?
is that something you do?
와우, 이건...
Wow, that's...
당신 매우 관대하군요.
That is so generous of you.
비용이 들거요.
Oh, it'll cost you.
오.
Oh.
네, 어...
Okay, uh...
우리 비용에 대해 협의를 해야겠군요.
We should discuss some sort
of financial arrangement
어..
in which I... I, uh...
오.
Oh.
알았어요!
Okay, then!
세상에.
Jesus.
들어오세요.
Come on in.
방해하려는 건 아니었어요.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
전혀요. 그냥 열 좀 식히고 있었어요.
Not at all. I was just
blowing off some steam.
- 소리가 너무 좋네요.
- 고마워요.
- You sound good.
- Thank you.
머리속이 깨끗해지죠. 연주해볼래요?
Clears the head. You play?
오, 고등학생 때 배우려고 했었지만,
Oh, I tried to learn in high school,
여자 마음을 얻는데에
더 쉬운 방법이 있다는 걸 깨달았죠.
but then I decided there were
easier ways to get girls.
음, 당신도 스트레스를 풀 게 있으면 좋겠네요.
Well, I hope you've got a way to decompress.
누구든 그런 건 필요하죠.
Everybody needs something.
적응은 잘 되나요?
How you settling in?
좋아요.
Great.
어, 이건... 저한테는 한 단계 더 나아가는 거에요.
Uh, it's... ?it's quite a step up for me.
우린 당신이 들어와서 좋아요.
Well, we're happy to have you.
뭐든 필요한 게 있으면 알려주세요, Jimmy.
Just let us know if there's
anything else you need, Jimmy.
고마워요... Cliff.
Thanks... Cliff.
음, 여기 오게 돼서 행복하네요.
Um, I'm happy to be here.
좋네요.
Great.
어, 다시 일하러 가볼게요.
Uh, better get back to it.
네, 저도요. 그래야겠죠.
Yeah, me, too, I suppose.
엄...
Um...
사실 제가 뭔가를 좀 찾았는데요.
Actually, um, ?I might
have found something
초반에 조사된 것 중에요.
in the initial disclosures.
- 오 그래요?
- Schweikart랑 Cokely는 계속해서
Oh, yeah? Schweikart and
Cokely keep referring to
"선택적인 용돈 프로그램"이라고 하고 있는데,
the "optional allowance program,"
제가 거주자들의 계약 번호를 확인해봤어요.
but I checked a number
of residents' contracts.
누구 한 명도 참여하지 않은
사람이 없었어요, 이건 제 생각에
Not a single one has opted out,
which makes me think
금전 협의에 있어 좀 더 의무적이었다고 생각해요.
it's more of a mandatory
financial arrangement.
그래서 당신은 그게 허점이라
상대측이 파고들 거라고 생각하는건가요?
And you're thinking that's
the "failure to state a claim"
that they filed in their answer?
상대측이 계속 이게 선택적이었다고
주장하면, 자발적인 게 되겠죠.
They keep saying it's optional,
thereby voluntary.
제 생각엔 우리가 반론할 수
있을거라 생각해요.
I think we can counter that
"참여한다"에 대한 동의가
거주함에 있어 요구조건이었다면
if "opting in" is a requirement
for residency,
물론 그렇게 보이구요,
which it sure seems to be,
자원봉사자들은 어불성설이라더군요.
well, their voluntary claims
don't hold water.
여기 뭔가 있는 것 같군요.
Might be on to something here.
잘 했어요, Jimmy.
Nice work, Jimmy.
고마워요, Cliff.
Thanks, Cliff.
♪
안녕하세요.
Hola.
안녕하십니까.
Hola. 쩔c처mo est찼s?
어서오세요. 무엇을 도와드릴까요?
Welcome. How can I help you?
어, 견적을 부탁하고 싶은데요.
Um, I was hoping to get an estimate.
제 차요. 제 차요
Uh, mi car. Mi coche.
차도 취급하죠?
You do cars?
네, 자동차요. 언제나요. 아.
S챠. Cars. Todo el tiempo. ?ah.
제 시트를 천갈이 하고 싶은데요.
I... I was hoping to get
my seats reupholstered.
엄... 음...
Um... Mm.
음, 한 번 보실래요? 보실래요?
Um, take a look? 쩔mira?
- 조금만 기다려주세요
- 네, 네, 네, 네.
- Un momento.
- S챠, s챠, s챠, s챠.
감사합니다.
Gracias.
네.
Yeah.
뭔가 새로운 걸 생각하고 있어요.
Thinking something new.
오래된 것엔 관심이 덜 가는 법이죠.
Give the old girl a little love.
이 일을 하는 건 좋은데, 그의 돈으로는
새 차의 계약금에 쓰는 게 나을거야.
그는 당신이 돈을 모아서 새 차를 사라고 하네요.
He said you should save
your money and get a new car.
그래요? 글쎄, 이건 감정적으로 가치가 있어서.
Yeah? Well, it has a sentimental value.
- 고전적인 차네요.
- 그쵸.
- Classic car.
- Mmm.
어떤 걸 원한대?
음, 어떤 재질로 해드릴까요?
Um, what material do you want?
글쎄, 가죽이라는 건 확실하죠.
Well, I was thinking leather, definitely.
어, 아마 악어 가죽?
Uh, maybe alligator.
선생님. 너무 비싸요.
Se챰or. Too much money.
네, 하지만 말했듯이, 이건 감정적으로 가치가 있어서요.
Yeah, but like I said,
it has a sentimental value.
내 생각에 이국적인 느낌의 가죽은 안 어울릴 것 같은데.
이런 느낌의 차에는 뭔가 좀 더 일관된 느낌은 어떨까
설득시켜봐.
그가 말하기를, 어, 악어 가죽은 안 어울릴 것 같대요.
He says, uh, alligator's
gonna look all wrong.
싼 게 더 좋을거에요.
Cheaper might be better.
음, 당신이 고른 걸 보여주시오.
Well, show me what you'd pick.
오, 죄송합니다, 선생님.
Ooh. I'm sorry, se챰or.
어, 제 아들이... 도와줄겁니다.
Uh, my son... He... He will help you, okay?
고르는 걸 도와드려.
비싼 거 사게 하지 말고, 알았지?
아, 감사합니다
Ah, mucho gusto.
절 어떻게 찾았죠?
How'd you find me?
여기 왜 왔나요?
Why are you here?
야구 카드.
Baseball cards.
내 생각에는, 너는 그 중년의 위기같은 차를 봤고,
The way I figure, you saw that
mid-life crisis of a vehicle
그 남자랑 관계를 끊기 위해 현명한 선택을 했어.
and wisely decided
?to cut ties with the man,
그리고 나는 널 비난하지 않아...
나도 그랬으니까.
and I don't blame you... I did, too.
그리고 넌 그에게 바가지 씌우려 했겠지.
And then you ripped him off.
그리고 그 야구 카드들이
And I'm sure those baseball cards
용돈벌이에 쉬운 방법으로 생각했을테고.
looked like an easy way
to make a few extra bucks
그 바보를 보내버리고, 교훈도 주고.
off that idiot, teach him a lesson, too.
하지만 넌 과소평가한 게 있어.
But you underestimated
너가 다루고 있는 사람이
얼마나 바보인지 말이야.
just how big an idiot you were dealing with.
아뇨, 전 꽤 잘 알고 있는데요.
No, I am pretty aware.
글쎄, 그렇다면 넌 과소평가한거야.
Well, then, you underestimated
그가 그 카드에 얼마나 집착하는지...
how attached the man was to those cards...
너무 집착해서, 그것들을
도둑맞았다고 경찰을 불렀지.
so attached, he called the police
and reported them stolen.
이제 경찰들이 그 사람 주변을 캐고 있어.
Now they're nosing around.
그건 "당신"이 문제에 처한 것 같네요.
That sounds like a "you" problem.
아니, 난 이게 꽤나
"우리"가 문제에 처한 것 같은데.
No, I think it's very much an "us" problem.
저는 단지 제 기회를 잡은 것 뿐인데요.
Yeah, I guess I'll just
have to take my chances.
하지만 행운을 빌어요.
But [Whistles] Good luck to you.
있지, 당신이 우리의 딜레마를 보고
You know, I was hoping you'd see our dilemma
옳은 일을 하면 좋겠는데.
and do the right thing.
하지만 우리가 여기서 할 수 있는 건
But I think what we have here now
당근과 채찍 인 것 같군.
is a carrot-and-stick situation.
오 그래요?
Oh, yeah?
이게 채찍이라구요? 네?
This the stick? Hmm?
당신이 여기 와서, 우리 가족을 위협하는 거?
You coming here, threatening my family?
네?
Huh?
당신은 더 큰 채찍이 필요할거요, 노인네.
'Cause you're gonna need
a bigger stick, old man.
난 여기에 당신 가족을 위협하러 온 게 아니라네.
I'm not here to threaten your family.
그리고 그 채찍의 이름은 Tuco Salamanca지.
And the name of the stick is Tuco Salamanca.
이제, 말하자면, 너는 협조하지 않을테고,
Now, you don't play ball, so to speak,
Tuco는 너의 그 조그만 곁다리 사업을 알게 되겠지.
and Tuco finds out about
your little side business.
충분히 큰 채찍인가?
That a big enough stick?
하지만, 나는 당근을 더 선호한다네.
However, I prefer the carrot.
당신도 그럴거라 생각해.
I think you will, too.
그게 뭔데요?
And what would that be?
넌 나한테 야구 카드를 돌려주고,
You give me back the baseball cards,
만불을 현금으로 줄 것,
$10,000 in cash,
그리고 당신은 대략 잡아서... 6만불은 벌 거라네.
and you net roughly... roughly... $60,000.
대체 그게 어떻게 되는거죠?
And how exactly does that work?
Chuck: Ernesto?
Ernesto?
Hey.
어디 가세요?
Going somewhere?
응, 우리가 가지.
Yes, we are.
Pryce: 내 차는 코너를 돌 때 꽤 까다로워.
She's a little tricky around the corners.
그리고...
So...
그리고 프리미엄 가스로 사용해줘.
And you got to go with the premium gas.
물론 사기같긴 하지만, 이거 큰 차이라구.
I know it seems like a scam,
but it makes a huge difference.
그리고 일주일에 최소 한 번은 세차해야 하고.
And I would get her washed
at least once a week.
스프링에는 핸드 왁스를 발라야 해.
And spring for the hand wax.
클리어 코트를 위해 보호막을 발라야 할거야.
You're gonna want that
extra layer of protection
for the clear coat.
최고의 대우를 받아야 해.
She deserves the best.
자동차 분해하는 곳(chop shop)에서 일하는
사람들한테 확실히 해두지.
I'll make sure the boys at the chop shop
가장 신사적으로 대하라구.
are real gentle with her.
잠깐. 왜?
Wait. W-why?
안돼.
No.
당신은 내가 저걸 타고 다니길 바라는거야?
You think I'd be caught dead
driving that thing?
저건 마치 6살짜리 포주가 타고 다니는
스쿨버스 같아.
It looks like a school bus
for 6-year-old pimps.
됐어, 이제 움직여도 되나?
All right, shall we move this along?
Aaron.
오케이, Jeter도 있고.
Okay, there's Jeter.
좋아. 오케이.
All right. Okay.
Mantle. Mantle. Matle이다.
Mantle. Mantle. There's Mantle.
다 됐나?
We good?
어, 네, 모두 있는 것 같네요.
Uh, yeah, that looks like everyone.
네, 다 여기 있어요. 모두 여기 있네요.
Yeah, they're here.
?looks like everyone's here.
이제 다른 물건 차례일세.
And now the other item.
이제 우리 사이의 거래는 다 끝난겁니다.
And now our business is concluded.
저기, 제대로 사과할게요.
You know, I can't help thinking
an apology was in order.
어, 이건... 또 경찰이네요.
Uh, it's... it's the police again.
샌드파이퍼는 우리의 요청에
Sandpiper hasn't really responded
아무런 대답이 없네요.
to our discovery requests.
서류 작업만 산더미인데,
They've buried us in paperwork,
사실 이 사건에 관련된 서류는 있지도 않아요.
but nothing actually relevant
to the particulars in this case.
별로 놀랍지도 않군.
No real surprise there.
우린 은행 기록에 대해 소환장을
발부할 수 있을거야.
We may have to subpoena their bank records.
고마워, Erin. 그리고 Jimmy.
Thank you, Erin. Jimmy.
고객 응대는 어떻게 되고 있나?
How we doing with client outreach?
우리가 소환장을 기다리는 동안,
Oh, while we're waiting on those subpoenas,
제 생각에는 고객분들이 그들 스스로
I'm thinking we should t
wrangling some of this stuff
이 사건에 맞서 싸울 수 있도록
해야할 것 같아요.
from the clients themselves.
이 사람들의 대부분은 이 모든 것에
대한 사본을 갖고 있어요.
Most of these folks
have hard copies of everything
going back to the Eisenhower administration.
물론, 그것 중 일부는, 어...
Of course, given some of their, uh...
모순되어 있는 것들이 있죠.
Inconsistent organizational practices,
이건 정말 시간이 오래 걸릴거에요.
it's gonna be slow going.
방해해서 정말 죄송합니다.
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
어, 한 여성분은, 음, 그녀는 상냥하지만,
Uh, this one lady, um, she's sweet,
어, 문에 달린 못처럼 귀가 먹었어요.
but, uh, deaf as a doornail.
그녀는 그녀가 가진 서류들을 기억...
She keeps all of her paperwork
in, um, she keeps it...
미안하지만 잠시 실례하겠네, Jimmy.
I'm sorry. Excuse me, Jimmy.
모두들 핸드폰, 전자 열쇠,
I'm gonna need everybody's phone,
그리고 전자 기기를 다 보관해주게나.
key fobs, and electronics.
Chuck. 어서오세요.
Chuck. Welcome.
앉으시죠.
Please. Have a seat.
저는 신경쓰지 마세요.
Don't mind me.
안녕하세요, 모두들.
Hey, everybody.
방해해서 죄송하군요.
Sorry for the interruption.
제가 없다고 생각해주세요.
Just pretend I'm not here.
당신이 와서 좋군요.
Happy to have you.
Jimmy, 어디까지 했지?
Jimmy, where were we?
어, 네.
Uh, yeah.
그래서, 제가 하고 싶은 말은...
So, I was saying...
음...
Um...
어, 고객분들로부터 서류를 얻어서...
Uh, getting the documents
from some of the clients...
분명 몇 분들은 쓸모 없는 걸
모아놓고 있을겁니다.
We definitely have some pack rats.
그분들에게 축복이 있길.
God bless 'em.
전 샌드파이퍼 산타페 지부에 있는 Gusdorff 씨를 방문했어요.
I was visiting Mrs. Gusdorff
at, uh, Sandpiper Santa Fe,
그리고 전 그 날 오후 내내 건초더미처럼 쌓여있는
and I spent the whole afternoon
sorting through just a haystack
영수증과 반 값 쿠폰 같은 걸 정리했어요.
of recipes and half-off coupons
from big lots.
하지만 이제 우리는 그 분의 월차 계산서를 갖고 있죠
But now we've got copies of
this woman's monthly statements
1997년 3월부터요.
going back to March 1997,
그러니까 이건 꽤 노동이 드는 일이겠지만,
so it might be a little labor-intensive,
우리의 고객들은 항상 우리에게 있어 최고의 자산이죠.
but our clients will always be
our best resource.
그리고, 그들은 리본 사탕도 갖고 있죠.
Plus, they have ribbon candy.
Chuck: Jimmy.
Jimmy.
안녕?
Hello?
여기서 뭐해?
What are you doing here?
내 이름이 이 빌딩에 붙어있다고.
?My name is on the building.
당신이 와줘서 너무 좋아요.
So great to have you here.
뭐든 필요하다면, 제 사무실로 오세요.
If you need anything, I'll be in my office.
여기 왜 왔어?
Why are you here?
증언하려고.
To bear witness.
Jame McGill입니다.
James McGill.
Ehrmantraut라네.
It's Ehrmantraut.
당신 여전히 비도덕적인 일을 하는가?
You still morally flexible?
만약 그렇다면,
내가 부탁할 일이 하나 있다네.
If so, I might have a job for you.
언제, 어디요?
Where and when?
앉으시죠.
Take a seat.
Wormald씨, 얘기하러 와주셔서 감사합니다.
Mr. Wormald, thank you
for coming in and talking to us.
네, 당연하죠.
Yeah, of course.
네, 저희가 사건 현장에 나갔던 경찰관들의
보고서를 봤는데요,
Yeah, we've been looking at the reports
that the officers took at the scene,
질문 몇 개가 있습니다.
and we have a few
?small follow-up questions.
아, 시간을 뺏어서 죄송합니다.
그냥 일반적인 절차에요.
Uh, sorry to waste your time.
Just standard stuff.
여기 정말 변호사를 데려오지 않으셔도 되세요.
There's really no need
for a lawyer to be here.
전 여기에 고문 역할로 왔습니다.
I'm here in more of an advisory capacity.
Dan이 그냥, 어, 옆에
우호적인 사람을 두고 싶어하더군요.
Dan just, uh, wanted
a friendly face next to him.
Coleman: 음, 우리들도 다 친절하게 대한답니다.
?Well, we're all friendly here.
우릴 보세요. 네 명의 친구들이라니!
Look at us. Four friends.
저흰 그냥 사실을 알고 싶은 겁니다.
We just want to get the facts straight
그래야 우리가 당신이 잃어버린 걸 찾을 수 있죠.
so we can, um, help you get
your property for you.
네, 저기 말이죠, 어, 괜찮아요.
Yeah, you know, uh, it's fine.
어, 도와주실 필요...
Uh, yeah, there's no need to, uh...
아닙니다, 이건 단지 일반적인 절차에요.
No, it's just standard procedure.
경찰관들이 항상 우리가 필요한 모든 정보를
You know, ?officers don't always get
보고서에 적어놓진 않거든요.
all the information we need in their report.
저흰 단지 당신의 야구 카드를 훔쳐간
사람을 찾고 싶은 것 뿐이빈다.
We just want to find the guys
who took your baseball cards.
네, 그거, 어...
Yeah, that's, uh...
있죠, 제 사촌이 Ty Cobb 담배 카드를 갖고 있어요.
You know, my uncle
?had a Ty Cobb tobacco card.
그걸 6인치 유리통에 보관하더라구요
Kept that thing behind six inches of glass
모나리자처럼요.
like it was the Mona Lisa or something.
와우, Ty Cobb요?
Wow. Ty Cobb?
그한테 조명을 어둡게 하라고 하세요.
Tell him to keep the lights low.
인공적인 조명이라도 어느 정도의
Even artificial lighting
has a certain amount
자외 복사선이 나오거든요, 어...
of ultraviolet radiation
that can, uh, you know...
- 오랜 시간 놔두게 되면...
- 네.
- Over the long term...
- Yeah.
음, 저희한테 정확히 설명해주실 수 있으신가요?
Um, can you just remind us
당신이 카드를 집 안 어디에 보관했는지?
exactly where you kept
your cards in the house?
네, 음, 어, 제가 말하고 싶은 건,
이건 더 이상 문제되지 않는다는 거에요.
Yeah, well, uh, as I was trying
to say, it's no longer an issue.
전 그걸 찾았거든요.
I found them.
카드를 찾았다구요?
So you found the cards?
어, 넵.
Uh, yep.
전 그냥 여기 와서 말하고 싶었어요,
음, 직접요.
I just wanted to come down and
tell you, you know, in person.
당신이 그걸 찾았다구요?
You found them?
어디서요? 집 주변에서요?
Where? Around the house?
아뇨. 저는, 음, 사설 탐정을 고용했어요.
No. I, uh, I hired a private investigator,
그리고 그가 도둑들을 뒤쫓았구요.
and he tracked them down.
그러니 그렇게 된거죠.
So, yeah.
정말요? 그들을 어디서 찾았대요?
Really? So, where were they?
있죠, 괜찮아요. 정말루요.
You know, it's fine. It is.
저는 정말... 당신들을 방해하고 싶지 않아요.
I really... I ought to get out of your hair.
어, 당신들은 저한테
충분히 많은 시간을 쏟으셨어요.
Uh, you've wasted enough time on me.
아뇨, 아뇨, 이건... 괜찮아요.
이게 저희 일인걸요.
No, no, it's... ?it's okay. It's our job.
저희는 단지 사실을 알고 싶은 것 뿐입니다.
We just want to get the facts right
사건을 종결할 수 있도록 도와드리죠.
so we can help close this case for you.
끝났어요.
It's done.
사건 종결됐다구요!
Case closed!
전 단지... 전 당신들이
I just... I know how much, you know,
얼마나 많은 일을 하고 있는지 알아요.
you guys have on your hands,
살인자, 강도, 갱 같은 것들요. 저는...
like murderers and robbers
and gangs and stuff. I...
이봐, Danny,
나가서 좀 쉬다 오는 게 어때?
Hey, Danny, ?why don't you get some air?
커피도 마시고.
You can have some coffee.
내가 형사들하고 얘길 끝낼게.
I'll finish up ?with the detectives here.
그럼, 본론으로 들어가볼까요.
Okay, let's get down
to brass tacks here, guys.
제가 추측하기론 당신네들의
두 명의 제복입은 경찰관들이
I'm guessing your two
fine uniformed officers
Wormald씨의 집에서
조그만 은신처를 찾은 것 같군요.
found Mr. Wormald's little hidey hole,
그리고 그것 때문에 당신 둘이 이렇게나
and that's why you two are so interested
내 친구를 "돕기" 위해 혈안이 된 거구요.
in "helping" my friend here.
이해해요.
I get it.
걸레받이에 숨겨진 공간이라니...
A hiding place in the baseboard...
누구든 의심가게 만들거에요.
it's gonna make anyone suspicious.
하지만 여기에 그 어떤 불법적인 것도
없다는 걸 장담하죠.
But let me assure you there's
nothing illegal going on here.
그럼 왜 그가 그렇게 불안해하는거요?
Then why is he so nervous?
으흠. 정말이지 그 식은땀은 의심간다고.
Mm-hmm. 'Cause I must say, the
flop sweat is kind of suspect.
우리 모두 각자의 비밀이 있잖아요, 그쵸?
We all have our secrets, don't we?
그리고 우리 중 죄가 없는 사람이 있나요?
And who among us is without sin?
그리고 그런 죄들이
모두 범죄라 할 수 있는 건 아니죠.
But those sins aren't all
of the criminal variety,
Wormald의 죄도 그렇구요, 그쵸?
and neither are Mr. Wormald's, okay?
하지만, 그들은 다들 사생활이 있다구요.
They are, however, very private.
사생활이라, 뭐 마약 딜러 같은걸 말하나?
Private, like drug dealer, maybe?
아뇨, 아뇨!
No, no!
그는 그저 이게 민감한 주제라
얼버무리는 거라구요.
He's being evasive because
it's a sensitive subject,
매우 예민하고, 그리고 법적으로
아무 문제가 없는 거지요.
very delicate, and of no concern
to law enforcement.
있죠, 우리도 정말 당신의 말을 믿고 싶은 것 만큼
You know, as much as we'd love
to, um, take your word for it,
우리도 이것보단 좀 더 해야해요.
we're gonna need a little more than that.
알았어요, 음, 이 모든 게 결국
개인적인 분쟁으로 요약되는군요.
All right, well, this all comes
down to a personal dispute.
그것으로 끝나는 겁니다.
That's all.
이건... 이건 Wormald 씨와
It's... it's between, um, Mr. Wormald
그리고, 어...
그의 예술 후원자 사이의 일이에요.
and, uh... his art patron.
- "예술 후원자"?
- 네.
- "Art patron"?
- Yeah.
어, 제 고객은 한 부유한 신사분과 계약을 했어요.
Uh, my client has an arrangement
with a wealthy gentleman
Wormald씨는 그 신사분에게
for whom Mr. Wormald provides...
Wormald씨가 만드는 예술 작품을
신사분의 관대함의 대가로 제공합니다.
Art in exchange for
?this gentleman's generous, uh...
저흰 그걸 후원이라 부르구요.
We'll call it patronage.
예술 작품이요? 예를 들어... 어떤거요? 그림이요?
Art? Like... like what? Paintings?
이건 좀 더 디지털 미디어에 가까워요.
It's more like digital media.
디지털 미디어?
Digital media?
그는 영상을 만듭니다.
He made videos for the man.
어떤 종류의 영상이요?
What kind of videos?
예술적 본능에 대한 개인적인 영상이요.
Private videos of an artistic nature.
그게 그 숨겨진 공간에 있었던 겁니다.
That's what was in the hiding place.
그걸 위해 만들어진 곳이에요.
That's what it's for.
그래서, 그 예술 후원자가
영상과 야구 카드를 훔쳤다구요?
So, this art patron stole the
videos and the baseball cards?
음, 뭔가 잘못 이해하셨네요.
Well, there was a misunderstanding.
제 말은, 어, 이걸 창작의 차이라 말하고 싶네요.
I mean, uh, ?call it creative differences.
예술가들은 변덕스러운 사람들이잖아요.
Artists are volatile creatures.
이봐요, 이 모든 건 연인간의
다툼에서 벌어진 일이에요, 네?
Guys, this all comes down
to just a lovers' spat, okay?
법적으로 허가된 두 명의 성인이
사이가 틀어진거라구요.
Two consenting adults had a falling out.
그렇게 된 일이에요.
That happens.
그리고, 어, "후원자"가 그 영상을 훔쳤고
And the, uh, "patron" stole the videos
그리고 야구 카드두요.
아마 본인의 생각을 전달하기 위해서겠죠.
and the baseball cards, uh,
to "make a point," I guess.
하지만 여기서 가장 중요한 건, 모두 해결됐습니다.
But the headline here is, it's all settled.
마음은 나았고,
Hearts have mended,
Wormald씨는 고소하지 않겠답니다.
and Mr. Wormald will not
be pressing charges.
그 영상에 뭐가 있는건가요?
What was on these videos?
- 그건 사생활입니다.
- 그렇게 말하시겠죠.
- They were private.
- You've said that.
그들은 감각을 자극하는 영상을 찍었어요.
They were videos intended
to titillate the senses.
- 네, 그럼 포르노군요.
- 아뇨. 아뇨!
- Okay, so porn.
- Not... no.
보통 말하는 그런 건 아닙니다.
Not as such.
엄밀히 말하자면,
페티쉬 비디오로 분류할 수 있겠네요.
Technically, they would be
categorized as fetish videos.
하지만 하나도 불법적인 건 없습니다.
But nothing illegal.
한 남자만 나오구요, 옷을 다 입은.
Just a man... a fully
clothed man, I might add...
덧붙이자면, 모두 그 혼자 하는겁니다.
just all by himself.
그냥... 그냥 Wormald씨가
옷을 다 입고, 어... 네.
Just... just Mr. Wormald
fully clothed, uh, yeah.
- 그런거죠.
- 알겠습니다.
So... all right.
그래서, 옷을 다 입은 Wormald씨가
혼자 뭘 하는건가요?
So, fully clothed Mr. Wormald
by himself doing what?
네, 이봐요. 뭔가요?
Yeah, come on, man. What?
스쿼트 코블러요.
Squat cobbler.
스쿼트 코블러가 뭔데요?
What's a s-squat cobbler?
스쿼트 코블러.
그게 뭔지 아시잖아요.
Squat cobbler.
?You know what squat cobbler is.
아뇨, 몰라요...
스쿼트 코블러가 뭔지 모르는데요.
No, I don't... I don't know
what a squat cobbler is.
저도 몰라요. 그게 뭔가요?
No, me neither. What is it?
네? 두 분 경찰 맞으세요?
What? And you two guys are cops?
호보켄 스쿼트 코블러요.
Hoboken squat cobbler.
보름달 문파이요.
Full moon moon-pie.
보스톤 크림에 철푸덕!
Boston cream splat.
진짜 몰라요?
Seriously?
색골 얼뜨기 사이먼.
Simple-Simon-the-ass-man.
네덜란드산 사과 궁둥이.
Dutch apple ass.
이봐요, 제가 영어 쓰고 있는 거 맞죠?
Guys, am I not speaking English here?
빌어먹을 스쿼트 코블러가 뭔데?!
What the hell is a squat cobbler?!
파이 위에 앉은 남자에요!
It's when a man sits in pie!
그가 파이 위에 앉는다구요!
He sits in a pie!
그리고 그는... 그는
씰룩씰룩거리면서 돌아다녀요.
And he... he wiggles around.
Hellmann의 마요네즈 같은 거라구요.
※ 미국의 마요네즈 브랜드
Maybe it's like hellmann's mayonnaise.
록키 산맥 서쪽에선 또 다른 이름으로 불려요.
It has a different name west of the rockies.
모르지만요.
하지만, 어, 엄밀히 말하자면,
I don't know. But, uh, technically,
그는 우는 남자 버전으로 해요,
그러니까 눈물을 흘리죠.
he does a crybaby squat, so there's tears,
이건 좀 더 특별한 버전이에요.
which makes it more specialized.
파이에 앉는 모든 남자가 울진 않아요.
Not all pie sitters cry.
제가 뭘 하나 알려드리죠.
But I'm gonna tell you something.
이 남자는 평범한 줄리안 무어(Julianne Moore)에요.
This guy is a regular Julianne Moore
눈물 흘리는 작업에 착수하기만 하면요.
once he gets ?the waterworks cranked up.
파이?
Pies?
뭐요? 사과로 만든 것 같은거요?
What? Like apple?
이봐요, 저는 영화 제작자가 아니라구요.
Guys, I'm not ?the
filmmaker here, all right?
바나나 크림. 어, ... 복숭아.
Banana cream. I... uh, peach.
오, 그리고... 관련된 코스튬을 입고 해요.
Oh, and there... And there
is a costume involved.
당신 우릴 엿 먹이려는 거지?
You got to be shitting us.
제가 꾸며낸 것처럼 보이겠죠.
Yeah, like I would make this up.
이봐요, 세상엔 다양한 사람이 많아요, 친구들.
Hey, the world is
?a rich tapestry, my friends.
근데 이번엔 절 믿어주세요.
But trust me on this.
당신들 정말 보고 싶지 않을거에요.
You don't want to see it.
그래서, 어, 우리 괜찮은거죠?
So, uh, we're good, right?
네. 괜찮아요.
Yeah. Great.
근데, 아주 작은 할 일이 있어요.
There is, however, one little,
tiny hanging Chad.
음, 뭔데요? 어떤 할 일이요?
Well, what? What Chad?
당신 비디오를 하나 찍어야 할거에요.
You're gonna have to make a video.
Kim: 잠깐. 잠깐.
Wait. Wait.
그래서 그는 파이를 먹은거야,
아니면 그냥 거기 앉은거야?
So he eats the pies or just sits in them?
둘 다. 너가 원하는 거 뭐든.
Both. Whatever you want.
뭘 먼저 하는데?
Which comes first?
어, 그건 찍는 사람 마음이지.
Uh, it's dealer's choice.
거기서 눈물이 나오는거지, 그치?
That's where the crying comes in, right?
이건 틀림없이 이기는 게임이었어.
That's a safe bet.
넌 대체 그런 걸 어떻게 생각해낸거야?
How the hell ?did you come up with that?
너가 나한테 백만년의 시간을 준다 해도
If you gave me a million years,
난 그래도 그런 거 못 지어낼거야.
I still would not have come up with that.
뮤즈가 있어.
The muse.
그녀가 날 통해 말을 하는거야.
She speaks through me.
난 겸손한 매개체일 뿐이라구.
I am but a humble vessel.
그리고 그들이 믿었고?
And they bought it?
- 응.
- 와우.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
내가 의심을 풀게 하는데 쓰인
뻔한 시나리오 몇 개를 들어봤지만
I've heard some far-out
scenarios used to sow doubt,
이건 진짜 상으로 케익을 줄만해.
but this definitely takes the cake.
Kim, Kim, Kim.
- 상으로 파이를 줄만해.
- 그래.
- Takes the pie.
- Yeah.
미안.
Sorry.
나 지금 당장 지붕으로
뛰어 올라가야 할 것 같아.
I should just jump off the roof right now.
그래, 너도 너 스스로의 악함을 느껴보라구.
Yeah, you should feel bad about yourself.
세상에, 하나 더 얘기해봐.
Jesus, can you tell a story.
음, 공정하게 말해서,
실제로 찍은 비디오가 대단했지.
Well, to be fair, I think it was
the video that clinched it.
무슨 비디오?
What video?
잠깐, 잠깐. 너...
너 정말 비디오를 찍은거야?
Wait, wait. You...
?You actually made a video?
이것 먼저 말하자면,
마지막에 가선, Dan이 정말 열심히 임했어.
I got to say, in the end,
ol' Dan really committed.
그 눈물을 믿었다니까.
I believed the tears.
어, 이건 남은 것들이야.
여분으로 남겨둔 것들.
Um, this is a leftover prop. It was extra.
우리가 얼마나 많이 찍어야
할지 확실하지 않아서, 많이 샀거든.
I wasn't sure how many takes
we would need, so I over-bought,
근데 내가 약속하는데,
이건 사람 궁둥이에 닿지도 않았어.
but I promise you,
?untouched by human buttocks.
너 증거를 조작한거야?
You fabricated evidence?
난 비디오를 찍은거야.
I made a video.
증거도 아니라고.
Not exactly evidence.
그걸 이용해서 고객이 무죄임을 입증했잖아.
You used it to exonerate a client.
고객이 무죄임을 입증하기 위해
위조된 증거를 이용했어.
You used falsified evidence
to exonerate a client.
음, 내 생각에 넌 너무
지나치게 생각한 것 같아.
Mm, I think you're splitting hairs.
지나치게 생각한 게 아니야.
I'm not splitting hairs.
너가 위증한 걸 Davis & Main에서
알아내면 어떻게 해?
What if Davis & Main find out
you faked evidence?
그 사람은 Davis & Main 고객이
아니었는걸.
It wasn't a Davis & Main client.
이건 그냥, 작은 무료 법률 상담이었어.
It was some nothing, little pro-bono thing.
이건 근무 시간 외의 업무였어.
이건, 어, 완전 내 혼자만의 일이었다구.
It was off the clock. It was,
uh, totally my own thing.
왜?
Why?
넌 여태껏 가졌던 일 중
최고의 직업을 갖고 있는데
Why would you risk
?the best job you've ever had
왜 굳이 무료 법률 상담을 위해
그런 위험을 감수하는거야?
for some pro-bono case?
난 그냥 내 친구한테 호의를 베푼거야.
I was doing a favor for a friend.
변호사 자격을 박탈당할 위험을 감수하면서?
그건... 그건 대단한 친구네.
Risking disbarment?
That's... that's some friend.
괜찮아! 이건... 먹혔잖아.
It's fine! It... it worked out.
Davis & Main은 여전히 모르고 있어.
Davis & Main are none the wiser.
Jimmy, 넌 위험한 짓을 했어.
Jimmy, ?you're playing with fire here.
넌 그 때 불평하지 않았잖아
I didn't see you complaining
그 때, 어, 지난 번에
허세남 Ken이 술 값을 낼 때.
when, um, Ken the douchebag paid
our bar bill the other night.
그것도 법적으로 조금 문제 되는 행위였어.
No, that was a little bit
of rule breaking right there.
그리고 내가 기억하기론, 넌 그걸 즐겼다구.
And if I remember correctly, you liked it.
많이.
A lot.
그건 이거랑 완전 다른 일이야.
That is so not the same thing.
어떻게? 뭐가 다른데?
How? What's the difference?
그건 우리 직업과 관련이 없잖아.
That had nothing to do with work.
우린 그냥... 방탕하게 논거라구.
And we were just... just screwing around.
이거?
This?
이건 위증이야.
Fabricating evidence.
Jimmy, 이거 진짜 널
위험에 빠뜨릴 수 있어.
Jimmy, ?this could really hurt you.
만약 그들이 찾아내면,
만약 그들이 잡는다면...
If they find out, if you get caught...
그들은 아무것도 찾을 수 없을거야.
It... they're never gonna find out.
진짜로? 저 밖에 심각한 범죄가 있는거야.
Seriously? You sound like
every dumb criminal out there.
만약 이걸 계속하면, 그들은 찾아낼거야.
If you keep this up, they will find out.
뭘 위해서, Jimmy?
For what, Jimmy?
중요한 게 뭐야?
What is the point?
난 이런 거 듣고 있을 수 없어.
I cannot hear ?about this sort of thing.
다시는. 알았어?
Ever again. Okay?
나 진지해, Jimmy.
I mean it, Jimmy.
듣지 않게 될거야.
You won't.